Bruno Longo

QA Automation and QA Engineer Coordinator

Hello HR/Recruitment Team, my name is Bruno Longo and I live in Brazil. I work as QA for almost 10 years now. During this time I already worked as a manual QA, Tech Lead, QA Coordinator, QA Automation Engineer and QA Architect.

At this moment I'm working as a QA Automation Engineer (or Quality Engineer) and Automation Architect Engineer.

My background on multiple clients and with big international companies made me a great problem solver and conflicts manager.

I have a great learning curve with both technical frameworks and business rules.

Thanks for the opportunity.

Best Regards.

Bruno Longo

EXPERIENCE

BairesDev (Gateless Client) - Remote

Feb 2022 – Present

QA Engineer & Test Automation Architect Engineer

Currently, I'm working on a team with Kanban framework as a Quality Engineer developing an automation with both Robot Framework and Cypress framework integrated with AWS connections and GitLab for CI/CD and Pipeline. I also run manual tests on Postman and create test cases and test plan.

<u>Technologies/Tool/Frameworks used</u>: GitLab, AWS, Robot Framework, Cypress, JavaScript, PowerShell, JIRA, React, API, Clojure, API Applications, Web Applications, Trunk Based Development, Git Version Control System, Agile, Kanban, Confluency.

Ambev (AB-InBev) – Bees Force

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

System Dev. Analyst & Test Automation Architect

Feb 2021 – Feb 2022

Technical Team Leader, QA Engineer Coordinator & Test Automation Architect

I worked with both, Agile frameworks Scrum (2 teams) and Kanban (1 team). I utilized JIRA to manage project artifacts and QA artifacts, such as Test Cases, Test Cycles and Test Execution Records. I also implemented an Automated Test PIPELINE with Robot-Framework running in Azure DevOps integrated with

Browser Stack for mobile and web applications, the framework was implemented to validate API/Microservices as well. Used Robot to implement test on mobile using the Appium library, for the web using Selenium and Browser library's and for API/Microservices I used the Rest library. During this time, I also created, managed and executed test cases related to Mobile, API, Web Applications and report QA Metrics. I implemented an Automated Data Mass using Postman. I coordinate, support and assist at career development of 9 QAs and I work as Automation Architect and focal point for a team of 25 QAs.

QA Engineer Coordinator for a Value Stream.

QA Architects for Test Automation PIPELINE with Azure DevOps.

Test on Mobile Digital Application.

Test on Web Admin Application.

Focal Point for Critical Demands.

Creation and Management of QA artifacts.

Management of Web Deploys as also Focal Point on Mobile Deploys.

Defect Management.

Test Case Creation and Execution (System Test, Interaction Test, Regression, Exploratory and Smoke Test).

Test Cycle Schedule and Management (System Test, Interaction Test,

Regression, Exploratory and Smoke Test).

Test Automation Engineer with Robot-Framework.

Tech & Team Leader for 3 teams.

Critical Enhancement Focal.

API applications test.

Focal Point to Product Expansion for other countries.

Requirement's elicitation.

AQuA & Interrupt Tests for Mobile Application

<u>Technologies used</u>: Azure DevOps, Git Version Control System, Jira, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Robot Framework, React, API/Microservices & Architecture, AQuA & Interrupt Mobile Test Frameworks, Mobile Applications, Web Applications, Trunk Based Development, GitFlow Development, Confluency, Stoplight, Browser Stack, Postman, Root Cause Analysis Process.

IBM

Nov 2018 – Oct 2020 Quality Assurance Tester

I worked as QA Analyst and Technical Lead for a Telecom provider testing financial systems and Ericsson's Billing Systems. I worked with the Dynamic Automation Team implementing a Web Portal using React and JavaScript to connect it with GitHub and manage issues on Ansible Automation (Tower – RedHat). I utilized Robot-Framework to implement API/Microservices tests using Rest library and Selenium library to test the automation on the Tower Application.

During this time, I also created, managed and executed test cases related to Mobile, API, Web Applications and reported QA Metrics. I managed, supported and assisted in career development of 6 QAs and I worked as the automation's focal point for the team.

Test on Mobile Digital Application and Legacy TELECOM System's.

Focal Point on Critical Demands.

Creation of QA artifacts.

Demands Planning and Management.

Defect Management.

Test Case Creation and Execution (System Test, Interaction Test and Smoke Test).

Team Leader Backup.

Critical Enhancement Focal.

API applications test.

SOAP applications test.

React Forms Developer with GitHub API integration.

Test Automation Engineer with Robot-Framework.

<u>Technologies used</u>: SOAP, GitHub, Git Version Control System, API/Microservices, Web Applications, Microsoft Team Foundation Service, Robot Framework, IVR, GitFlow Development, React, Carbon Design System, Mobile Applications, IBM Rational Team Concert, IBM Rational Quality Center, HP Application Lifecycle Management, Ericsson Billin System, Capsettle, SCTR (TIM Italy), Ansible, Tower (RedHat), Warehouse Management System, Postman.

MHA Sistemas

Mar 2018 – Nov 2018 Quality Assurance Tester

Small business where I implemented a new QA Team and all the QA processes. I implemented test automation to legacy systems. During this time, I also created, managed and executed test cases related to Web Applications.

Test on custom applications.

Test on WMS System.

Detect Manager.

Focal Point on IBM RQM and JIRA.

Test Cases Creation and Executions (Integration, System, Homologation, Unit, Regression).

Requirement's elicitation.

Test Automation with Selenium

Sustain.

<u>Technologies used</u>: Warehouse management system, IBM Rational Quality Manager, Jira, QA Best Practices.

IBM

Jun 2013 - Nov 2017

Quality Assurance Tester & Technical Interaction Leader

I worked as QA Analyst with focus on critical enhancements for more than 8 different clients. Additionally, I worked as Interaction Technical Lead for an education company and an international assurance company focused on Web Applications, Web Administration Portal and Oracle Data Base. I managed releases and workflow as well as QA activities with a team of 3 to 6 QAs depending on the sprint time and the client. I implemented the Scrum Board using the IBM Rational Team Concert, I managed Release Defects and was responsible for the RCA (Root Cause Analysis). During this time, I created, managed and executed test cases related to Mobile, API, Web Applications and reported QA Metrics.

Technical Interaction Leader.

Homologation Focal Point.

Test on custom applications.

Test on ERP SAP systems.

Creation of test artifacts.

Defect Manager.

Focal Point on IBM RQM.

Test Cases Creation and Executions (Integration, System, Homologation, Unit Regression).

Requirement's elicitation.

Worked with international clients such as AIG, Mondelez, General Motors, Sprint, DirecTV and others.

<u>Technologies used</u>: SAP ERP, MySQL, Oracle, IVR Systems, IBM Rational Team Concert, IBM Rational Quality Center, HP Application Lifecycle Management, HP Quality Center.

COURSES & TRAININGS

IBM

IBM Agile Explorer, 2020 IBM Automation Essentials, 2020 DevOps Essentials, 2020 Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner, 2020

SCRUMstudy

Scrum Fundamentals Certified, 2020

CertiProf

Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate, 2020

Udemy

Test Automation with Robot Framework – Basic, 2020

Skillsoft

Ansible: Ansible for DevOps Provisioning, 2020

DevOps with Ansible: Working with Ansible Features, 2020

QA Ninja

Learning the Capybara Power Testing a Clone Tinder Web Application with Cucumber and Ruby, 2020

Testing a Trello Clone Application with Java and Selenide, 2020

LanUniversity

SAP ERP

SAP Academy Sales and Distribution, 2015

EDUCATION

Senac

Postgraduated Degree in Information Technology Management and Governance, 2021

Veris IBTA Metrocamp

Bachelor's Degree in System Information, 2014

SKILLS

- Manual Testing (9 Years)
- Test Automation (5 Years)
- Automation Architect (3 Years)
- Technical Lead (5 Years)
- Engineer Coordinator (<2 Years)
- Postman (3 Years)
- QA Metrics (5 Years)
- Oracle (1 Year)
- Agile (5 Years)
- .NET (<1 Year)
- PL/SQL (<1 Year)
- HP Quality Center (2 Years)
- HP Application Lifecycle Management (1 Year)
- IBM Rational Quality Manager (5 Years)

- Microsoft Team Foundation Service (2 Years)
- Unit Test (<1 Year)
- Warehouse Management System (7 Years)
- Telecom Testing (5 Years)
- IVR Testing (3 Years)
- Red Hat (<1 Year)
- Carbon (<1 Year)

- React (<1 Year)
- GitHub (4 Years)
- Microsoft Office (10 Years)
- HTML (3 Years)
- Microsoft Windows (10 Years)
- SQL Server (3 Years)
- Java (<1 Year)
- JavaScript (<1 Year)
- Microsoft Excel (10 Years)
- C++ (1 Year)
- Microsoft Word (10 Years)
- Microsoft PowerPoint (<1 Year)

- C (1 Year)
- SAP SD (5 Years)
- IBM Rational Team Concert (5 Years)
- SAP Testing (5 Years)
- SOAP (5 Years)
- Azure DevOps (<2 Years)
- Jira (5 Years)
- Scrum (3 Years)
- Kanban (3 Years)
- Robot Framework (5 Years)
- SAP ERP (5 Years)
- MySQL (1 Year)